Anthony Joseph Marchitelli

732-927-0200 | Email | Github | Blog | Linkedin

Full Stack Developer

Full stack web developer with a passion for personal improvement and helping others. Experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React. Background in Operations Management with well developed skills in team-building and project management. Proven track record in helping companies attain and surpass their goals. Interests include problem solving and anything related to sports.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CSS | HTML | JavaScript | Phaser | React | React Native | Redux | Ruby on Rails | Ruby | Bootstrap | SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Fantasy Buddy - Github - Demo

A Fantasy Football App built with React Native

- Leverages NFL historic and real time statistics with implemented projections logic that will help users make the best decision
- Utilizes Redux to manage state, which is used to portray different information to the page
- Integrates React Navigation for a flawless transition between several screens within the application

Domain Modeler 5000 - Github

Project planning application built with React

- Implemented JavaScript to develop components with React for web
- Utilized Canvas with HTML to give Users the ability to draw and replicate a whiteboard
- Leveraged Ruby on Rails to save user information such as name and previous drawings

BlackJack - Github - Demo

A classic Blackjack game built with Ruby on Rails

- Leveraged card data and images from an external API
- Implemented RESTfull routes
- Utilized sessions and cookies to keep track of logged in user
- Custom CSS

Snake - Github - Demo

A twist on the classic snake game built with Phaser library

EDUCATION

Flatiron School-NY, NY 2019

Full Stack Development, Ruby on Rails and Javascript Program

Middlesex County College-Edison, NJ

• Credits towards Mathematics and Science degree

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

FedEx Ground, Woodbridge, New Jersey - Operations Manager

2013-2019

2017-2018

- Manage staff and assign tasks
- Ensure that all Fedex rules and safety procedures are followed
- Delegate tasks to workers ensuring all tasks are completed
- Ensure all work was done in the most efficient way possible by tracking efficiency of package handlers
- Motivate others to work to the best of their ability

ShopRite, Woodbridge, New Jersey - Deli Clerk

2011-2012

- Sanitized and cleaned work area daily
- Assisted with setting the schedule
- Worked in customer facing service role

Carteret Little League, Carteret, New Jersey - Umpire

2006-2011

- Officiated sporting events
- Maintained standards of play and ensured all game rules were followed